Guide to the Anson Phelps Stokes Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence of Anson Phelps Stokes, 1879-(1892-1958); PART I. I; 57.5 linear feet (139 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13
    - Lenox, Massachusetts, 150th anniversary celebration of Trinity Church, 1943 (Box 115, Folder 1977)
    - re: Lindley biography, 1940 January 1 - 1941 December 31; 1947 January 1 - 1954 December 31 (Box 115, Folder 1978-1979)
    - Lo-Lz, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 115, Folder 1980-1989)
    - Lohmann, Carl A., 1940 January 1 - 1942 December 31 (Box 115, Folder 1990)
    - Lohmann, Carl A., 1943 January 1 - 1949 December 31 (Box 115, Folder 1991)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 17/17
    - Lohmann, Carl A., 1950 January 1 - 1957 May (Box 115, Folder 1992)
    - Loram, Charles T., 1940 January 1 - July 9 (Box 116, Folder 1993)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 2/3
    - Loram, Hilda V., 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 1994)
    - Lucas, Canon Albert Hawley, 1940 January 1 - 1943 December 31 (Box 116, Folder 1995)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 19/14
    - Lucas, Canon Albert Hawley, 1944 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 116, Folder 1996)
    - Lucas, Canon Albert Hawley, 1949 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 1997)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1940 January 1 - 1947 December 31 (Box 116, Folder 1998)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1950 January 1 - 1952 December 31 (Box 116, Folder 1999)
    - Ma-Mb, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 2000-2008)
    - Mc-Md, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31; 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 2009-2014)
    - McCabe, Joseph, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 116, Folder 2015)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 4/34
    - Me-Mh, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31; 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 2016-2020)
    - Mental Hygiene, National Committee for, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 116, Folder 2021)
    - Mi-Mn, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31; 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 117, Folder 2022-2025)
    - Mitchell, Anna V.S., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31; 1956 July (Box 117, Folder 2026)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1940 January 1 - 1942 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2027)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1943 January 1 - 1946 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2028)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1947 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2029)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 12/7
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1949 January 1 - December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2030)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1950 January 1 - April 30 (Box 117, Folder 2031)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1950 May 1 - August 31 (Box 117, Folder 2032)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 10/2
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1950 September 1 - December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2033)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 4/1
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1951 January 1 - 1955 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2034)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 117, Folder 2035)
    - Mitchell, Clarence V.S., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2036)
    - Mitchell, Mildred [Mrs. Clarence B. Mitchell], 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2037)
    - Mo-Mt, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 117, Folder 2038-2047)
    - Molteno, Lucy, 1949 April 30 (Box 117, Folder 2048)
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1940 January 1 - 1941 December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2049)
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1942 January 1 - December 31 (Box 117, Folder 2050)
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1943 January 1 - December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2051)
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1944 January 1 - 1945 December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2052)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 17/24
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1946 January 1 - December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2053)
    - Moulton, Harold G., 1947 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2054)
    - Mu-Mz, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 118, Folder 2055-2059)
    - Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 118, Folder 2060)
    - N, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 118, Folder 2061-2073)
    - New York Trust Company, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 118, Folder 2074)
    - New York Trust Company, account of Carol M. Phelps Stokes, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 118, Folder 2075)
    - re: Committee on the American Negro in the Defense Industry, 1940 January 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2076)
    - O, 1940 January 1 - 1946 December 31 (Box 118, Folder 2077-2081)
    - O, 1947 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 119, Folder 2082-2086)
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1940 January 1 - 1941 December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2087)
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1942 January 1 - 1943 December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2088)
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1944 January 1 - December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2089)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/20
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1945 January 1 - June 30 (Box 119, Folder 2090)
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1945 July 1 - December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2091)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 15/8
    - Ogilby, C.F.R., 1946 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2092)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 0/3
    - Oldham, J.H., 1940 January 1 - 1945 December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2093)
    - Oldham, J.H., 1946 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 119, Folder 2094)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 6/10
    - Pa-Ph, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 119, Folder 2095-2106)
    - Pate and Robb, insurance, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 119, Folder 2107-2111)
    - Patterson, Frederick D., 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 120, Folder 2112)
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1940 January 1 - 1941 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2113)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 14/22
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1942 January 1 - December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2114)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/17
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1943 January 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2115)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 11/17
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1945 January 1 - 1946 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2116)
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1947 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2117)
    - Pepper, George Wharton, 1949 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 (Box 120, Folder 2118)
    - Peyton, Dr. Thomas Roy, 1943 June - 1944 February (Box 120, Folder 2119)
    - Phelps-Stokes Corporation, 1940 January 1 - 1946 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2120)
    - Phelps-Stokes Corporation, 1947 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2121)
    - Phelps-Stokes Fund
      See: Part I, boxes 177-179
    - Pi-Pz, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 120, Folder 2122-2133)
    - Pierson, George W., Yale University, History Department re: Yale History, 1940 January 1 - 1943 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2134)
    - Pierson, George W. re: Yale History, 1944 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 120, Folder 2135)
    - Pierson, George W. re: Yale History, 1949 January 1 - 1950 December 31; 1952 February 21 (Box 121, Folder 2136)
    - Pierson, George W. re: Yale History, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 121, Folder 2137)
    - Poirier, Irene M., 1940 January 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2138)
    - Poirier, Irene M., 1945 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2139)
    - Poirier, Irene M., 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 121, Folder 2140)
    - Powell, The Rt. Rev. Noble, 1940 January 1 - 1941 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2141)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 38/46
    - Powell, The Rt. Rev. Noble, 1942 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2142)
    - Powell, The Rt. Rev. Noble, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 121, Folder 2143)
    - Price, Harry B., 1940 January 1 - December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2144)
    - Princeton University, honorary degree, 1956 January 1 - December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2145)
    - Q, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2146)
    - Ra-Rh, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 121, Folder 2147-2154)
    - Ri-Rn, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 121, Folder 2155-2159)
    - Ro-Rz, 1940 January 1 - 1945 December 31 (Box 121, Folder 2160-2165)
    - Ro-Rz, 1946 January 1 - 1955 December 31 (Box 122, Folder 2166-2171)
    - Ro-Rz, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 122, Folder 2172)
    - Correspondence with the Rockefeller Foundation re: publication of Church and State
      See: Church and State correspondence, Part I, box 103, folder 1742
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 122, Folder 2173)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940 January 1 - 1950 March 31 (Box 122, Folder 2174)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1940 January 1 - 1945 October 31 (Box 122, Folder 2175)
    - Roy, L.A., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 122, Folder 2176-2180)
    - re: Gasoline rations, 1942 January 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 122, Folder 2181)
    - Sa-Schm, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1955 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 122, Folder 2182-2190)
    - St. Paul's School, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 122, Folder 2191)
    - Sakai, Barnabas T., 1946 November 14; 1947 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 122, Folder 2192)
    - Sakai, Barnabas T., 1949 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 122, Folder 2193)
    - Sakai, Barnabas T., 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 122, Folder 2194)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 3/0
    - Schn-Sg, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 123, Folder 2195-2201)
    - Sh-S1, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1955 October 20; 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 123, Folder 2202-2207)
    - Sheldon, James, 1940 January 1 - 1943 December 31 (Box 123, Folder 2208)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 16/17
    - Sheldon, James, 1944 January 1 - 1947 December 31 (Box 123, Folder 2209)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 23/19
    - Sheldon, James, 1948 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 123, Folder 2210)
    - Shipherd, H. Robinson, proofreader Church and State, 1949-1951, 1956-1958 (Box 123, Folder 2211)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 42/41
    - Shipler, Guy Emery, 1940 January 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 123, Folder 2212)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/23
    - Shipler, Guy Emery, 1945 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1955 March 28 (Box 123, Folder 2213)
    - Sm, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 124, Folder 2214-2215)
    - Smith, Edwin W., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 124, Folder 2216)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 26/64
    - Sn-Ss, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 124, Folder 2217-2222)
    - St-Sz, 1940 January 1 - 1948 December 31 (Box 124, Folder 2223-2233)
    - St-Sz, 1949 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 125, Folder 2234-2236)
    - Stockbridge Bowl Association, 1946 January 1 -1947 December 31; 1948 September 20 (Box 125, Folder 2237-2238)
    - Sweet, William W., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 125, Folder 2239)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 21/21
    - Ta-Th, 1940 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 125, Folder 2240-2250)
    - Ti-Tz, 1940 January 1 - 1945 December 31 (Box 125, Folder 2251-2255)
    - Ti-Tz, 1946 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 126, Folder 2256-2260)
    - Tobias, Channing H., 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 126, Folder 2261-2264)
    - Trinity Church, Lenox re: calling of a Rector, 1948 January 1 - 1949 December 31 (Box 126, Folder 2265)
    - U, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 126, Folder 2266-2267)
    - V, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 126, Folder 2268-2271)
    - Wa-Wd, 1940 January 1 -1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 126, Folder 2272-2277)
    - We-Wh, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1955 November 16-1958 August 13 (Box 127, Folder 2278-2285)
    - Lewis S. Welch, Inc., 1940 January 1 - 1955 December 31 (Box 127, Folder 2287-2290)
    - Wi-Wn, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1956 January 1 - 1958 August 13 (Box 127, Folder 2291-2296)
    - Wo-Wz, 1940 January 1 - 1950 December 31, 1958 August 13 (Box 127, Folder 2297-2300)
    - X-Y-Z, 1940 January 1 - 1943 December 31, 1945 January 1 -1958 August 13 (Box 128, Folder 2301-2306)
    - Yale University, Divinity School, 1947 January 1 - 1950 December 31 (Box 128, Folder 2307)
    - Letters to APS from co-workers in the field of Negro education upon his resignation as Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1946 November - December (Box 128, Folder 2308)
    - Letters of congratulations to APS upon his receiving the Churchman of the Year Award, 1951 September - October (Box 128, Folder 2309)
    - Letters of congratulations on Golden Wedding Anniversary of APS and CMPS, 1953 December (Box 128, Folder 2310)
    - Letters to APS on his 80th birthday, 1954 April 13 (Box 128, Folder 2311)
    - Letters of sympathy received by the Stokes family after the death of Anson Phelps Stokes, 1958 August (Box 128, Folder 2312)
    - Letters of sympathy received by the Stokes family after the death of Anson Phelps Stokes, 1958 August (Box 128, Folder 2313)
    - Undated letters, A-Z, 1892-1958 (Box 128, Folder 2314)
    - Keys to the original filing system for correspondence by Rosalie Malone, secretary to APS, 1944, 1951, undated (Box 128, Folder 2315)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Halkett, Sarah M.P. (Stokes) [sister of APS]
      - 1881, 1900-1903, 1920-1943 Feb 6, no date (Box 129, Folder 2316-2320)
      - Sympathy letters received on the death of Sarah Stokes Halkett., 1943 (Box 129, Folder 2321)
    - Hatch, Daniel Lindley [grandson of APS]
      - 1954 Oct 2 (Box 129, Folder 2322)
    - Hatch, John David, Sr. and family
      - 1943-1953 (Box 129, Folder 2323)
    - Hatch, John David, Jr. [son-in-law of APS]
      - 1939 Jun-1958 Aug 13 (Box 129, Folder 2324-2326)
    - Hatch, Olivia E. Phelps (Stokes) [Mrs. John D. Hatch, Jr., daughter of APS]
      - 1926 Jan 1-1958 Aug 13, 1967, n.d (Box 129, Folder 2327-2332)
      - Correspondence re: her securities and investments; New York Trust Co., Higginson, and McCulloch, 1929-1930 (Box 129, Folder 2333)
      - Hatch-Stokes wedding arrangements, 1949 August 1 - September 30 (Box 129, Folder 2334)
      - Hatch-Stokes wedding arrangements, 1949 October 1 - December 31 (Box 129, Folder 2335)
    - Hawkins, Robert and Elizabeth [Helen Elizabeth Phelps Stokes Hawkins, daughter of Harold Phelps Stokes]
      - 1947, 1950-1956 (Box 129, Folder 2336)
    - Hedstrom, Ethel (Hoyt) Peale [niece of APS]
      - 1929, 1957
    - Hooker, Mildred E.P. (Stokes) [Mrs. Ransom S. Hooker, Sister of APS]
      - 1903, 1927-1928, 1930-1940 Jan 1 - 1946 Dec 31, 1951 Jan - 1957 Dec 31 (Box 129, Folder 2338-2341)
    - Hooker, Dr. Ransom S. [brother-in-law of APS]
      - 1923 - 1958 Aug 13 (Box 129, Folder 2342)
    - Hooker, Ransom S. [nephew of APS]
      - [1922?], 1929 (Box 129, Folder 2343)
    - Hoyt, Amy (Moore) [Mrs. Anson Phelps Stokes Hoyt]
      - 1947 Nov 18 (Box 130, Folder 2344)
    - Hoyt, Anson Phelps Stokes [nephew of APS]
      - 1925-1958 (Box 130, Folder 2345)
    - Hoyt, Edwin and Molly
      - 1940-1949 (Box 130, Folder 2346)
    - Hoyt, Ethel Stokes [niece of APS]
      See: Ethel H. Peale Hedstrom, Part I, box 129, folder 2336
    - Hoyt, Ethel V.P. (Stokes) [Mrs. John Sherman Hoyt, sister of APS]
      - 1903, 1924, no date (Box 130, Folder 2347)
      - 1925-1949 Dec 31, no date (Box 130, Folder 2348-2350)
    - Hoyt, Graham [nephew of APS]
      - 1926-1958 (Box 130, Folder 2351)
    - Hoyt, Helen Phelps
      See: Helen Phelps Hoyt Stookey, Part I, box 139, folder 2541
    - Hoyt, John Sherman [brother-in-law of APS]
      - 1903; 1921-1927; 1930-1958 Aug 13 (Box 130, Folder 2352-2354)
    - Hoyt, Sherman Reese [nephew of APS]
      - 1931, 1935 (Box 130, Folder 2355)
    - Hunter, Caroline M.P. (Stokes) ("Carrie") [Mrs. Robert Hunter, sister of APS]
      - 1899; [1903-1904]; 1920-1921; 1924; 1926 May - 1927 May; 1927 Nov - 1929 Mar; 1930-1958 Aug 13 (Box 130, Folder 2356-2361)
    - Hunter, Caroline [niece of APS]
      - 1932, 1947, no date (Box 130, Folder 2362)
    - Hunter, Edith (Chamberlain) [Mrs. Phelps Stokes Hunter]
      - c. 1934 (Box 130, Folder 2363)
    - Hunter, Margaret Truax
      - 1947 (Box 130, Folder 2364)
    - Hunter, Phelps Stokes [nephew of APS]
      - 1928-1929, 1937-1938 (Box 130, Folder 2365)
    - Hunter, Robert [brother-in-law of APS]
      - [1903] (Box 130, Folder 2366)
      - 1922, 1927, 1935-1938 (Box 130, Folder 2367)
    - Katzenbach, Nicholas and Lydia [Lydia Phelps Stokes Katzenbach, daughter of Harold Phelps Stokes]
      - 1946-1956 (Box 130, Folder 2368)
    - Ketcham, Anne Phelps (Stokes) [Mrs. Orman Ketcham, niece of APS]
      - 1947 Sep 16 (Box 130, Folder 2369)
    - Ketcham, Orman W. [married Anne Phelps Stokes, daughter of Harold Phelps Stokes]
      - 1947-1953 (Box 130, Folder 2370)
    - Merrill, Edwin K.
      - 1930 Jun 1 - 1950 Dec 31; 1956 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13 (Box 130, Folder 2371-2374)
    - Merrill, Helen Phelps (Stokes) [Mrs. Edwin K. Merrill, niece of APS]
      - 1937 Jan 1 - 1950 Dec 31 (Box 130, Folder 2375)
    - Mitchell
      See: box 2, folders 27-30 See: box 34, folders 555-565 See: box 35, folder 572 See: box 78, folders 1281-1294 See: box 79, folder 1303 See: box 117, folders 2026-2037 See: box 117, folder 2048 See: box 132, folders 2398-2431
    - Phelps, Sarah King [grandmother of APS]
      - 1893 Oct 17 (Box 130, Folder 2376)
    - Slade, Francis Louis
      See: Part I, box 43, folder 717 See: Part I, box 91, folders 1486-1487
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps [father of APS]
      - 1879, 1887, 1892-1906 (Box 131, Folder 2377-2378)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps III [son of APS]
      - 1920-1946 Dec 31, no date (Box 131, Folder 2379-2397)
    - Stokes, Carol (Mitchell) Phelps
      - (from APS), 1903 October 1 - October 30 (Box 132, Folder 2398)
      - (to APS), 1903 October 1 - October 31 (Box 132, Folder 2399)
      - (to APS), 1903 November 1 - November 30 (Box 132, Folder 2400)
      - (from APS), 1903 November 1 - November 30 (Box 132, Folder 2401)
      - (to APS), 1903 December 1 - December 31 (Box 132, Folder 2402)
      - (from APS), 1903 December 1 - December 31 (Box 132, Folder 2403)
      - (from APS), 1904 January 1 - 1905 December 31 (Box 132, Folder 2404)
      - (to APS), 1904 January 1 - 1905 December 31 (Box 132, Folder 2405)
      - 1906 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13 (Box 132, Folder 2406-2415)
      - (to APS), undated,[undated for period of 1903 October - Dec] (Box 133, Folder 2416)
      - (from APS), undated,[undated for period of 1904-1905] (Box 133, Folder 2417)
      - no date, [undated for period of 1912 Jan - Dec] (Box 133, Folder 2418)
      - [1904-1918?], no date (Box 133, Folder 2419-2427)
      - no date (Box 134, Folder 2428-2431)
    - Stokes, Edith (Minturn) [Mrs. I.N. Phelps Stokes, sister-in-law of APS]
      - 1896 (?), 1899, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 2432)
      - 1922-1930 Dec 31 (Box 134, Folder 2433)
    - Stokes, Elizabeth M. (King) [Mrs. Harold Phelps Stokes, sister-in-law of APS]
      - 1920-1958 Aug 13 (Box 134, Folder 2434-2435)
    - Stokes, Harold Phelps [brother of APS]
      - 1900; 1920-1949 Dec 31 (Box 134, Folder 2436-2449)
      - 1950 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13 (Box 135, Folder 2450-2451)
    - Stokes, Helen Elwood [second wife of W.E.D. Stokes, Sr.]
      - no date (Box 135, Folder 2452)
    - Stokes, Helen Louisa (Phelps) [mother of APS]
      - 1891-1908; 1910; 1912-1918; 1920-1924 Oct 31; 1924-1930 May 31, no date (Box 135, Folder 2453-2466)
      - no date (Box 136, Folder 2467-2468)
      - Sympathy letters received on the death of Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes, mother of APS, 1930 June - October (Box 136, Folder 2469)
    - Stokes, Helen Olivia Phelps [sister of APS]
      - 1922-1945 Dec 27 (Box 136, Folder 2470-2477)
      - Sympathy letters received on the death of Helen Olivia Phelps Stokes, sister of APS, 1945-1946 (Box 136, Folder 2478)
    - Stokes, Houston [son of W.E.D. Stokes, Jr.]
      - 1943 Jun 7 (Box 136, Folder 2479)
    - Stokes, Isaac Newton Phelps [brother of APS]
      - 1892, 1899, 1920-1924 Oct 31, 1924 Jun 1 - 1933 Dec 31 (Box 136, Folder 2480-2489)
      - 1934 Jan 1 - 1944 Dec 31 (Box 137, Folder 2490-2493)
      - Sympathy letters received on the death of I.N. Phelps Stokes, brother of APS, 1944 December - 1945 January (Box 137, Folder 2494)
      - Correspondence re: memorial tributes to Isaac Newton Phelps Stokes, 1945 January - February (Box 137, Folder 2495)
    - Stokes, Isaac Newton Phelps II [son of APS]
      - 1920-1921; 1924 Feb 1 - 1930 May 31; 1930 Jan 1 - 1946 Dec 31; 1947 Oct 1; 1956 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13 (Box 137, Folder 2496-2508)
    - Stokes, James Boulter [uncle of APS]
      - 1903 Oct 15 (Box 137, Folder 2509)
    - Stokes, James Graham Phelps [brother of APS]
      - 1899; 1920-1921; 1925-1958 Aug 13 (Box 138, Folder 2510-2516)
    - Stokes, Lettice (Sands) [Mrs. J.G. Stokes, sister-in-law of APS]
      - 1938 May (Box 138, Folder 2517)
    - Stokes, Olivia E. Phelps [aunt of APS]
      - 1903, 1906-1912 (Box 138, Folder 2518)
      - Correspondence re: historical manuscript of New England, 1913, 1914 (Box 138, Folder 2519)
      - 1916; 1920-1927 Dec 14 (Box 138, Folder 2520-2523)
      - Letters of sympathy to APS, financial appeals sent after her death, 1927 December 14 - 1928 March 12 (Box 138, Folder 2524)
    - Stokes, Olivia E. Phelps [daughter of Anson Phelps Stokes]
      See: Olivia E. Phelps (Stokes) Hatch, Part I, box 129, folders 2327-2335
    - Stokes, Samuel Newton [grandson of APS]
      - 1949 (Box 138, Folder 2525)
    - Stokes, Thomas Hoyt [grandon of APS]
      - 1944 Mar 30 (Box 138, Folder 2526)
    - Stokes, William Earle Dodge [uncle of APS]
      - 1903, 1920, 1921 (Box 138, Folder 2527-2528)
      - Copies of letters by W.E.D.S. to others, 1920-1921 (Box 138, Folder 2529)
      - 1922-1926 (Box 138, Folder 2530)
    - Stokes, William Earl Dodge II ["Weddie"] [cousin of APS]
      - 1920-1950 Dec 31; 1956 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13; no date (Box 139, Folder 2531-2539)
    - Stookey, Dr. Byron
      - 1937-1957 (Box 139, Folder 2540)
    - Stookey, Helen P. (Hoyt) [Mrs. Byron Stookey, niece of APS]
      - 1924, 1937-1956 (Box 139, Folder 2541)
    - Letters from APS to the Stokes family
      - 1948-1956 (Box 139, Folder 2542)
    - Contributions of APS to the Family News
      See: Part I, box 222, folder 29
- Journals, Speeches, Writings, and Research Materials, 1890-1958; PART I. II; 13.75 linear feet (35 boxes)
  This series is divided into four chronologically arranged sections: Journals and Memoranda, Articles, Addresses, and Public Statements, Reviews and Introductions, and Books.
  "Journals and Memoranda" consists of travel journals, diaries, memoranda and notes on a variety of subjects, and bibliographies of Anson Phelps Stokes's published works compiled by Stokes himself.
  The second section, "Articles, Addresses, and Public Statements," contains letters to the editor, articles, speeches, sermons, prayers, and memorial statements, in print as well as in outline or draft form. There is also correspondence (assembled by Stokes) commenting on certain of his articles.
  "Reviews and Introductions" consists of evaluations by Stokes of publications of others. Reviews of Stokes's books are filed in the fourth section of this series under the title of the book.